Muruges

Mobile: +65 8181 5627

Email: k.muruges@u.nus.edu

Skype ID: muruges95

GitHub Profile: https://github.com/muruges95

Bitbucket ID: muruges95

Online resume: https://muruges95.github.io/



Personal Statement

About Me

As a Computer Science undergraduate about to complete my 2nd year of studies at the National University of Singapore, I have undertaken internships and various projects from start-ups and as part of certain courses. These different opportunities have enabled me to develop not only specific IT industry experience, but also a valuable and transferable skill set in this fast-paced sector.

Work Experiences and Projects

Before enrollment into University, I worked at 361 Degree Consultancy, a company providing software solutions and accounting advisory. I worked as an IT Support Intern there for a period of 3 months and was tasked with providing client support and acted as an administrator for the company's database.

In the following summer, I worked as an Android App Developer for a local startup called DingleTutors. Right now, I am working with the same startup as a Full Stack Intern, to manage their database and website. I have also worked as a Teaching Assistant for 1 semester and tutored freshmen for a foundational Computer Science course. During this period, I conducted tutorial sessions for the students while creating and grading assignments.

Unique Skill Set

During all my work stints, I have been tasked with many problems that I have been expected to solve quickly and independently. Regardless of the situation, I have always been able to get the job done on time, one way or another. As a Teaching Assistant (TA), I was tasked with creating the first set of assignments for the cohort using Markdown and Latex despite having no prior experience in creating assignments or working with those languages. Despite this, I was still able to get it released on time for the students to attempt on our online programming environment. I also developed new ways to publish programming contests that were part of our course to make it easier for new TAs.

I have also been involved in teaching positions during many portions of my life, such as during National Service when I was an instructor for recruits in our Basic Military Training Center. These positions have allowed me to understand people and the problems they have better, making it easier to work with them.

How I Can Contribute

From my different work experiences and projects, I have obtained much experience on software engineering and full-stack development. In addition to Windows, I have been using a Linux OS for over a year, so I am proficient in it as well. I have also been learning about deep learning using the fastai library in my own time. I am confident that with any relevant roles, I will be able to not only contribute meaningfully via the technical skills I possess, but also be able to make the company function more efficiently.

Internship Objective

I hope that through this internship, I can get more meaningful work experience in the IT industry, whilst forming new connections with the people in the startup. I also wish to decide on what my future area of focus will be through my experience from the internship. Lastly, I want to experience what working in Silicon Valley will be like.

[K Muruges]

Education

Aug 2016 - Present

National University of Singapore
Bachelor of Computing (Computer Science)
(Course details in Appendix A)

Singapore

NUS High School of Mathematics and Science
High Distinction with Math and Chemistry Honors,
Physics and Economics Majors
Conducted an Advanced Research Project as a team of 2
Title: Self-assembly in coordination chemistry

Work Experience

Aug 2017 - Dec 2017 **NUS School of Computing** Singapore Teaching Assistant Taught a foundational computer science module Conducted tutorial sessions for freshmen Carefully mentored 8 students and worked through their queries Set and graded their assignments May 2017 - Aug 2017 **DingleTutors** Singapore Android App Developer (Orbital program) Worked as an Android developer for the startup DingleTutors Achieved highest level in the Orbital Program (Apollo 11) Carried out poster presentation attended by 100 teams Mar 2016 - June 2016 361 Degree Consulting Pte Ltd Singapore IT Support Intern Carried out onsite installation of software Set up local file-sharing networks and provided client support Acted as admin for company's server Dynamically tackled IT problems faced by colleagues

Scholastic Achievements/Extracurricular Activities

Aug 2016 - Present	Scholarship SPRING Executive Development Scholarship (EDS)	Singapore
May 2017	 Cyber Defenders Discovery Camp (CDDC) 2-day team competition to solve cyber security challenges Won second place prize of \$4000 	Singapore
Aug 2016 - Aug 2017	 Computing Club Committee Executive of Sports Committee Planned and conducted annual Sports Camp for 80 participants 	Singapore
May 2013 - Dec 2013	 Overseas Community Involvement Program (OCIP) Head of PR and Logistics for OCIP Raised over \$3000 for refurbishments in a Cambodian school 	Singapore

[K Muruges] 2

Skill Sets & Proficiency

Programming Java Proficient

Python Proficient **JavaScript Proficient** С Intermediate Ruby Intermediate

Shell Scripting **Basic**

Web HTML, CSS **Proficient**

Ruby on Rails Intermediate React Intermediate PHP Basic

Database PostgreSQL Intermediate

ActiveAdmin Intermediate

Version Control Git **Proficient** GitHub **Proficient**

Bitbucket Proficient

Mobile App Dev Android **Proficient**

Markdown Intermediate Markup

Intermediate AsciiDoc

XML Basic

Security Disassembly **Basic**

> File System Security Basic **Network Security Basic** Basic Firewall (iptables) **Basic**

Operating Systems Proficient Linux

Windows XP, 7, 10 **Proficient**

Productivity Tools Microsoft Word **Proficient**

Microsoft Excel **Proficient** Microsoft PowerPoint **Proficient**

Language Proficiency

Spoken English - fluent; Tamil - fluent

Written English - competent; Tamil - average

Additional Information

Learning about Deep learning using Python, through online fastai courses

Learning how to play the guitar

[K Muruges] 3 Degree: Bachelor of Computing (Computer Science)

Cumulative Average Point: 4.73 / 5.00

List of Courses

Туре	Course Description	Grades
Programming, Data Structures and Algorithms	Programming Methodology	A+
	Data Structures and Algorithms	A-
	Design and Analysis of algorithms	A-
	Discrete Structures	A-
General Computer Science Electives	Introduction to Computer Networks	A-
	Computer Organization	A-
	Introduction to Operating Systems	A
	Introduction to Information Security	A+
	Computer Security	In-progress
Math and Science	Linear Algebra 1	A-
	Calculus for Computing	A
	Physics 2	A
	Probability and Statistics	In-progress
Software Engineering	Orbital** (Independent Software Development Project)	CS
	Software Engineering	In-progress
Communication	Computing and Society	A-
	Roots and Wings – Personal and Interpersonal Effectiveness 1.0	CS
	Effective Communication for Computing Professionals	In-progress
General Electives	Quantitative Reasoning	A+
	The Biophysical Environment of Singapore	S
	Asking Questions	CS
	Traditional Chinese Knowledge of Health and Well-being	In-progress

^{*} **SPRING Singapore**, currently known as Enterprise Singapore, aims to grow stronger enterprises by transforming industries, building new capabilities, and providing Singapore companies access to global opportunities. For more information, head to: https://www.enterprisesg.gov.sg/

NUS Grading Scale:

^{**} **Orbital** was a summer project that was done between Year 1 Semester 2 and Year 2 Semester 1. Students taking part in the program worked in pairs and could choose the nature of their project and their area of focus. Along the way, teams received guidance on their rate of progress and other recommendations from mentors who were part of the program.

A+ & A (5.0); A- (4.5); B+ (4.0); B (3.5); B- (3.0); C+ (2.5); C (2.0); D+ (1.5); D (1.0); F (0)

S = Satisfactory; U = Unsatisfactory

CS = Completed Satisfactorily; CU = Completed Unsatisfactorily

EXE = Exempted; IC = Incomplete; IP = In Progress; W = Withdrawn